# Steve Stickel

Lead Software Developer

## Contact

#### **Address**

Summerville, SC, 29486

#### Phone

2489346619

#### E-mail

stevemstickel@gmail.com

#### www

https://tdsticks.github.io/

#### Skills

- POC / Prototyping
- Project Management
- Database Design
- Cloud Computing
- Solutions Architect

# Languages

- Python 13 yrs
- Django 3 yrs
- SQL 8 yrs
- Node.js 5 yrs
- React 1 yr
- AngularJS 3 yrs

Highly skilled software development professional bringing enormous talents for software design, development, and integration. Offering years of experience in providing solutions and architecture. Background in writing code and developing systems for internal and client-based applications.

# **Work History**

#### 2020-04 -Current

## **Lead Software Developer**

Latcha+Associates, Farmington, MI

- Lead architect and SME to various toolsets and development platforms including: Jira, Django and AWS.
- Created training materials on Jira and AWS for development teams.
- Architected cloud-based CMS with API for Ford pilot AR app using their WERS engineering codes to connect VIN data to marketing content.
- Created proof of concepts, such as Text-to-Speech generator using IBM Watson and image and video labeling service using AWS Rekognition.

## 2018-09 -2020-04

# Software Development Manager

Latcha+Associates, Farmington Hills, MI

- Managed small team of developers to help facilitate various email marketing projects for client facing VCI (VW/Audi Credit) account.
- Lead developer in enhancing our email marketing development workflow with Salesforce Marketing Cloud and other custom internal applications.

## 2016-03 -2018-11

# Senior Web Application Developer

Latcha+Associates, Farmington Hills, MI

- Developed internal web applications for clients and company use to help automate manual processes, such as building email seed list generator.
- Helped architect new email development pipeline for agency.
- SME for both Jira and Salesforce Marketing Cloud within marketing division.

2016-01 - 2016-03	CG Pipeline Developer  Latcha+Associates, Farmington Hills, MI  • Enhanced CG pipeline workflow and productivity by building custom tools, systems and scripts.
2012-02 - 2016-01	<ul> <li>Web Application Developer</li> <li>Latcha+Associates, Farmington Hills, MI</li> <li>Instrumental in creating Lincoln Experience iOS and Android app with content animation and PhoneGap / Javascript support.</li> <li>Architected and lead developer for Audi Marketing Activity Calendar (MAC) using Javascript and SIMILE library with team of other developers.</li> </ul>

# 2007-08 - **DevOps Engineer**

2012-02

With A Twist Studio, Rochester Hills, MI

- Oversaw and managed office hardware and software infrastructure.
- Improved upon CG pipeline typing together Shotgun Software, post-production software and render farm using Python and Bash.

## **Education**

1997-09 - 1999-06	Certificate in 3D Animation: 3D Art, Modeling and Animation
	School Of Communication Arts - Raleigh, NC
1993-09 - 1997-06	High School Diploma
	Troy High School - Troy, MI

# **Additional Information**

I enjoy writing trading bots for crypto and Forex markets in my spare time.